Hello everyone, today we are going to try out Dragon's Realm,
which is a modpack centered around Reika's mods.
As we spawn, we are welcomed by 8 different books.
But we are going to see them in detail later on.
For the moment, we shall explore this new world
where there are quite a few interesting things.
Such as weird structures that will turn our life into black and white if we get too close by.
We also have colorful threes with cryptic names.
And weird crystals on the surface.
However, since we could only find frozen biomes in this world, we decided to try making a second save.
And this time we found out how cool the rivers look in this pack.
However, in this save we could only find desertic biomes, so let's try again.
Third time the charm, we now have a proper spawn.
With a beautiful colorful forest close by.
And we also have both a desert and some snow too.
So, we pick a place where we can start founding our base and do the usual vanilla things to get started.
And, once the night comes, we go explore the caves under the surface.
Where we find some quite interesting things.
Such as weird geysers in random ore clusters.
And our exploration was quickly blocked by an uranium vein.
Getting close by will hurt us, but, luckily, we will be kept with 1 HP.
So, we leave the important stuff behind, take a breath and go try to remove the uranium.
After we verify the situation, we take back our equipment and start digging.
Once we removed all of the uranium, we deposit it in a place where it will hurt no one.
Such as a chest in the middle of our base.
We refill our health and hunger bar and then we go back to explore the mine shaft.
And the first cool thing we find in an unexplored dungeon is, yeah, more uranium.
This time, let's try a different route.
And we now have found a monolith and a sleepy gas vent.
Then we find a different poison source, a cave spider spawner.
Before venturing any further, let's collect some iron to make an armor.
Here irons spawn in veins.
Not as big as Gregtech ones, but not as small as Vanilla's.
With our new armor, we can get rid of the spawner, while also getting high on achievements.
Behind this annoyance, we find a tin ore vein,
which puts to use the textures from all the mods in the pack.
And after more exploration, we have found a third source of poison, gas vents.
One last thing I'd like to show you is the looks of lava lakes.
The lava stone makes them look way cooler, but also even more annoying than Vanilla ones.
Anyways, everything looks cool, but our main focus should be to collect some of each material we can manage to find.
And, once we get home, we get reminded of the good old times, when you had the same ore from different mods.
And we now have seven different forms of copper.
I mean, eight different copper ores.
Now that we have all that loot, we can smelt down a tiny amount of it and use that for some ore doubling machine.
We shall use the good old trusty pulverizer.
And we quickly set it up with an even older and trustier BuildCraft engine.
This machine will also turn each mineral into a dust of the same mod.
Next we make an induction smelter to obtain some invar.
We need it so that we can make a smeltery to get some good tools.
Or so we thought, until we noticed we also need steel for a smeltery that only goes up to 600 degrees.
So, instead, we go for a paper flint pickaxe
which we empower with a diamond to make it diamond-like but flint repairable.
This paper tool is now capable of mining obsidian, but it is still too slow and inefficient.
So we make an obsidian and paper hammer, which we fill with redstone so that we can gather more obsidian.
And, once we have some decent tools, we make a portal and go in the nether.
At first glance, it looked quite the usual nether
but, after moving a littel bit, we started to see that it is quite more annoying than usual
And things escalated quite quickly, just look and how intense the effects are in this place.
Anyways, after a lot of exploration, we have found what we were looking for,
a nether fortress and some blaze rods.
Next, we go visit a magical forest where we hunt a slime king, so that we also get some slime balls.
And I gotta say, just checking out that tree cleaned out my eyes from that hellish place we just run away from.
Once we get home, we use our new loot to craft and build a blast furnace, we went with the railcraft one.
And it was when we tried to use it, that we found out something was wrong.
Apparently, both railcraft and immersive blast furnaces require some enriched coal to work.
Luckily, we can quickly make it in a buildcraft assembly table.
So, we quickly make one, and also a laser to power it.
We power it, and, after a bit of time, we get our enriched coal.
And that machine just throws stuff on the ground.
Now we can finally make some steel.
We shall use the first ingots to make our first Reika machine, a RotaryCraft blast furnace.
Now, the temperature on that furnace is quite low.
To make it go at a usable temperature, we have to place it over a metric cube of hot magma.
Once it reaches 600 degrees, we can finally use it to make the most used metal of the whole modpack, HSLA steel.
And our first usage for it shall be a work table, required to make RF cables.
Then we make some RF storage cell
and we have completed our basic house.
We are now ready to start using Reika's mod.
But we shall do that the next episode.
Bye bye.